ANA STATE

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER



SUMMARY

I'm a multi-disciplinary designer who works at the intersection of business, user experience, and human psychology to help businesses build experiences & services people love.

My approach to design is driven by accessibility, user centricity & data as these are the three pillars of building great products that solve endusers problems and help businesses become successful.

EDUCATION

CAREER FOUNDRY

2018 - 2019

UX | UI & Voice Design

POLITECHNICA UNIVERSITY

2012 - 2014

MS Information Engineering & Computer Science

POLITECHNICA UNIVERSITY

2008 - 2012

BS Applied Electronics, Telecommunications & Information Technology

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Designer

Earnd - London

03/2020 - 07/2020

Earnd Rebrand App + Payroll Provider App Integration

- Lead the end-to end design of Earnd app integration with a Payroll Provider app from ideation to launch
- Conducted user research & usability testing to gather feedback that informed product's roadmap & design
- Worked closely with PM & Business peers to shape the product's design strategy
- Collaborated closely with the wider UK and AUS design teams to build & implement a design system

Senior UX|UI Designer

BCR Erste Group - Bucharest

07/2019 - 10/2019

eToken Redesign - George app

- Lead the end-to end UX process from ideation to launch, facilitating design sprints & raising awareness of UX process
- Conducted User Research to understand how people sign & authorise transactions within the current design determining user needs, current and potential target audience
- Turned Research insights into strategic drivers building Personas, & User journey maps that inform the app's redesign strategy, new user flows and features
- Used Prototypes to validate design decisions via A/B & Usability testing

Analytics Digital Lab

- Worked closely with Product Mgr, Business & Sales team to understand the landscape of the existing cross-sell process and identify pain points sales agents are faced with
- Alongside UX Researcher conducted in person-interviews in branches to understand how sales agents use the current software tools to build customer profiles and sell products

SKILLS SET

- Strategy: Design thinking, Design sprint facilitation, Lean UX, Concept Development.
- Research: User |
 stakeholders interviews,
 usability & A/B testing
 Personas & Information
 Achitecture
- Design: Wireframing, Prototyping, Motion Design

TOOLS I USE

- · Sketch, Figma
- Invision, InDesign,
- Principle, Flinto
- draw.io, Balsamiq
- Abstract, Zeplin
- Webflow, Adobe XD
- Slack, Trello

SELF TAUGHT ON

- HTML
- CSS
- WEBFLOW
- CSS FLEXBOX
- MySQL
- Linux
- Any design tool I use

OTHER SKILLS

I am multilingual and can speak English, Spanish, Italian, Romanian, and I am also learning Dutch. Used qualitative Research data to build Personas that outline sales agents' needs & feed the machine learning model developed by data science & engineering teams

Freelance UX|UI Designer

Freelance Project

04/2017 - Present

Alexa recipe skill

- Conducted competitive analysis to understand the voice assistants market & existing apps that use voice technology
- Used behavioural & research data to build Personas and to understand how users interact with voice assisted devices
- Designed the information architecture, initial code & voice scripts of the recipe app based on research data
- Collaborated with a developer to improve the back-end code of the app

Release Implementation Manager

KPN - Amsterdam

06/2018 - 12/2018

Future of Mobile Project

- Stakeholder coordination of the cross functional Release implementation process for multiple projects (migrations, monthly releases, application upgrades) for a web platform serving over 2 million subscribers
- Simplified the end-to end implementation process reducing the implementation time by 20%, through multi-disciplinary collaboration with QA, Dev engineering & Solution Architecture teams

Technical Services Manager

Huawei Technologies - Amsterdam

11/2015 - 05/2018

CCBS 2.0 Telfort Project

- Oversaw the implementation of 30 + upgrade projects, feature changes, maintenance projects of a 2 million end users web platform
- Worked closely with Technical, Business stakeholders & SA team mapping business goals & user needs and managing the Agile process to maximise value delivery for each implementation